A young girl cries for help ...
Lisa, Bright and Dark is a tv movie, drama film directed by Jeannot Szwarc.
Three teenage girls try to help their girlfriend, who is having a nervous
breakdown that conventional therapy seems to be failing to remedy.
Lisa Schilling, played by Kay Lenz.
Margaret Schilling, played by Anne Baxter.
William Schilling, played by John Forsythe.
Elizabeth, played by Anne Lockhart.
Mary Nell Fickett, played by Debralee Scott.
Betsy Goodman, played by Jamie Smith-Jackson.
Girl, Interrupted is a 1999 American biographical drama film directed by James Mangold and written by
Mangold, Lisa Loomer and Anna Hamilton Phelan, based on the 1993 memoir by Susanna Kaysen.
Starring Winona Ryder, Angelina Jolie, Clea DuVall, Brittany Murphy, Elisabeth Moss, Jared Leto, Angela Bettis, Jeffrey Tambor, Vanessa Redgrave, and
Whoopi Goldberg, the film follows a young woman who spends 18 months institutionalized at a psychiatric hospital following a suicide attempt.
Girl, Interrupted was theatrically released in the United States on
December 21, 1999, and grossed $48 million worldwide.
It received mixed reviews, but Ryder, Jolie and Murphy were praised; Jolie won numerous awards including the Academy Award for Best Supporting Actress, the Critics' Choice Movie Award for Best
Supporting Actress, the Golden Globe Award for Best Supporting Actress – Motion Picture and the Screen Actors Guild Award for Outstanding Performance by a Female Actor in a Supporting Role.
The tone is emotional.